麦琪:早上好,各位.
Maggie: Good morning everybody.
这是这个月的第二个星期六,你知道意味着什么吗?
It's the second Saturday of the month and you know what that means.
本:你变的古怪了?
Ben: You're gonna be cranky?
麦琪:不.是家务活日.别走!
Maggie: No.It's chore day.Freeze!
本:哦,行了.
Ben: Oh, come on.
开萝尔:但是我一直清洁洗手间,这不公平.
Carol: But I always have to clean the bathrooms, it's not fair.
麦琪:这次,我们的做法有些不同.
Maggie: Well this time, we're gonna do things a little differently.
我已经把所有的家务写在纸条上了,每个人可以抽取她或他将干的事情.
I've written down all the chores on slips of papers so each of us can
现在选择一个,本.
draw what he or she will do.Now pick one, Ben.
本:整理自己的内裤抽屉.
Ben: Organize my panty drawer.
麦琪:不,那是我的.那是我的.
Maggie: No, that's mine.That's mine.
本:不,不.你定的规矩.
Ben: No, no.Your rules.
麦琪:不,给我那张.
Maggie: No, give me that.
本:灰尘和真空吸尘器和清理……地毯.
Ben: Dust and vacuum and beat the...rugs.
开萝尔:打扫卫生间.妈妈,这不公平.
Carol: Clean the bathroom.Mom, it's not fair.
麦琪:哦,你绝对对,开萝尔.不公平.
Maggie: Oh, you're absolutely right, Carol.It's not fair.
开萝尔:那么我可以再次选择?
Carol: So I can pick again?
麦琪:不.
Maggie: No.
克莉丝:轮到我,轮到我.和芭比娃娃玩.
Chrissy: My turn, my turn.Play with your Barbie dolls.
开萝尔:等一下.她不认识!
Carol: Wait a second.She can't read!
克莉丝:哦,是的.
Chrissy: Oh, yeah.
麦琪:这,让我看看些什么了.粉刷车库.
Maggie: Here, let me see what that says.It says, paint the garage.
克莉丝:粉刷车库.行!
Chrissy: Paint the garage.Alright!
麦琪:不,不,不,
Maggie: No, no, no, no.This is for your father.
不.这是你爸爸的活.你为什么不就收拾你的玩具和密切注视本和开萝尔.
Why don't you just pick up your toys and keep an eye on Ben and Carol.
克莉丝:来吧,伙计们!开始干活!这不是你们娱乐的时间!
Chrissy: Come on you wussies!Let's get to work!It's not your time to play!
麦琪:哦,杰森,你真准时.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, you're just in time.
杰森:不,实际上我迟到了.你有见到迈克?
Jason: No, actually I'm late.Have you seen Mike?
麦琪:选一个.不是左边的那个.
Maggie: Pick one.Not the one on the left!
杰森:收拾我的玩具.好.
Jason: Pick up my toys.OK.
麦琪:不,不,不,不!
Maggie: No, no, no, no!Jason, stop that.
杰森,别这样.今天是家务日,这是你的主意,还记得?
It's chore day, it was your idea, remember?
杰森:哦,是今天吗?哦,我不能,亲爱的,我要去诊所.
Jason: Oh, is that today?Oh, I can't honey, I've got to go to the clinic.
麦琪:但是杰森,最近每个星期你都在工作.
Maggie: But Jason, you've been working every weekend lately.
杰森:是呀,
Jason: Yeah, but today we're having a special workshop on families that
但是今天我们有个家庭成员之间无法沟通的专题讨论.
don't communicate.
迈克:嗨,我很高兴,
Mike: Hey, I'm glad you guys are finally cleaning this place up.
你们把这地方打扫干净了.这原来就像是垃圾场.
It was really starting to look like a dump.
瞧这,有些谷物在地板上.
Look here, you've got some cereal on the floor.
麦琪:别那么轻松,迈克,
Maggie: Don't get too comfy, Mike,
你今天要帮助你父亲粉刷车库.
you're gonna help your dad paint the garage today.
迈克:什么,再说一遍?妈妈,我十年前刚干过这事.
Mike: What, again?Mom, I just did that ten years ago.
杰森:他不会!
Jason: He can't!
迈克:是的,是的,我不会!
Mike: Yeah, yeah, I can't!
麦琪:为什么不会?
Maggie: Why not?
杰森:因为处于对我的宠爱,他已经自愿去诊所,
Jason: Because as a favour to me,
麦琪.
he's volunteered to come down to the clinic today, Maggie.
迈克:是的,麦琪,我去……哪里?
Mike: Yeah Maggie, I'm going down to the...The where?
杰森:去那个四个月以来我每周六都去的地方.
Jason: To where I've been going every Saturday for four months.
迈克:哦,爸爸,我不想理发.
Mike: Oh, Dad, I don't want to get a hair cut.
杰森:不,是诊所,我自愿去的地方.
Jason: No, the clinic, where I volunteer.
迈克:哦,是的,是的!继续,我们要做些事情.
Mike: Oh, yeah, yeah!Go ahead, we'll do some shots and stuff.
克莉丝:妈妈,真空吸尘器是不是在火星四溅呢?
Chrissy: Mom, are vacuum cleaners supposed to throw sparks?
麦琪:本,当心我的吸尘器!
Maggie: Ben, be careful with my Suckmaster!
迈克:爸爸,快点,在妈妈回来之前,我们去看场电影.
Mike: Dad, come on, let's go to a movie before Mom gets back!
杰森:不,我们去诊所,迈克.
Jason: No, we're going to the clinic, Mike.
迈克:啊,行了,
Mike: Ah, come on, Dad.
爸爸.
I thought we just had a tender father-son moment here,
我想我们刚在这体验了父子之情,什么时候你帮我得到过去的妈妈.
where you helping me get one past Mom.
杰森:嗨,你知道这事很久了.
Jason: Hey, you've know about this for a long time.
我需要将这些事情写下来.
You gotta write these things down.
迈克:什么?写下来!喔……我是谁,你?
Mike: What?Write it down!Wh...who am I, you?
杰森:好,好.别帮我忙了.你就呆在家里,虚度一个放松的周六,不考虑任何人,除了自己.
Jason: OK, fine, fine.Don't do me this favour.You just stay around the house
lounging on a relaxing Saturday, thinking of nobody but yourself
迈克:行!是你说的.爸爸.
Mike: Alright!Now you're talking.Dad.
迈克:嗨,这里可不是我们耗光汽油的鬼地方.
Mike: Hey, this is not the kind of neighbourhood you wanna run out of gas in.
杰森:我们没有耗光汽油,迈克,我们在这.
Jason: We're not out of gas, Mike, we're here.
迈克:我们在什么地方?
Mike: We're where?
杰森:在诊所.
Jason: At the clinic.
迈克:哦,你,
Mike: Oh, man, if I had a free clinic,
如果我有免费诊所,我一定不会把它放在这么个鬼地方.
I certainly wouldn't put it in a crumby neighbourhood.
杰森:哦,那么你想选择富人区开免费诊所?嗨,
Jason: Oh, so you'd pick rich neighbourhood to put in a free clinic?
嗨,嗨!这车看起来是不是需要什么点缀一下?
Hey, hey, hey!Does this car look like it needs a hood ornament?
TC: 你在说我吗?
TC: You talking to me?
杰森:我刚花了四块钱把车打了蜡.
Jason: I just payed four Bucks to have this thing waxed.
迈克:哦,我希望他已经得急救.
Mike: Oh man, I hope he's got first-aid.
TC: What's a white guy like you doing in a neighbourhood like this
杰森: 我是一个白色的家伙!
Jason: I'm a white guy!
TC:  毫无疑问
TC: Most definitely.
杰森: 你好吗?
Jason: Hey!
迈克: 你认识这个家伙?
Mike: You know this guy!
Jason: You kidding.Everybody in a thirty block radius knows TC
TC:  40元,我这一周可真是忙.
TC: Forty blocks.I had a busy week.
杰森:这是我儿子,迈克.
Jason: This is my son, Mike.
迈克:哦……你好.你们两个怎么认识的?
Mike: Oh...hi.How do you two know each other?
TC: 你爸爸是我在危险期的评议员
TC: Your pop's my crisis councilor.
杰森:恩.怎么样,无论什么?
Jason: Mmm.How's it going, anyway?
TC: 三周没有...我在做,是的
TC: Three weeks without...I'm doing OK.
杰森:很好!是呀!我们下周再见你.
Jason: Alright!Yeah!Well I'm gonna see you next Saturday.
TC: 好吧, 我把它记下来,像你告诉我的那样
TC: Yeah, well I wrote it down like you told me.
杰森:很好.
Jason: Yeah.
TC: 嘿!只付四元的那个家伙已经让它增加了
TC: Hey!The man just paid four Bucks to have it waxed.
迈克:那么,这里到底是怎么回事,爸爸?
Mike: So, what exactly goes on in here, Dad?
杰森:我已经告诉你关于这个地方了,迈克.
Jason: I've told you about this place, Mike.
这是个免费诊所,在这我自愿和许多其他医生一起….那……在社区里帮助那些人.
This is a free clinic where I volunteer along with a lot of other doctors...
你在听我讲话,是吗?
Hello ...to help out in the community.You do listen to me, don't you?
迈克:啊?
Mike: Huh?
病人:这里有人会说西班牙语吗?
Patient: Does anybody here speak Spanish?
迈克:呃……不,但是我去过西班牙.
Mike: Err...no, but I've been to Spain.Dr.
贝茨医生:什么事?
Bates: Che Passa?
医生:啊,贝茨医生,
Doctor: Ah, Doctor Bates, I need your Spanish.
我需要你讲西班牙语.告诉她这是个小的骨折……她应该放弃溜冰.
Tell her it's a simple fracture...she should give up skateboarding.
杰森:迈克,过来.我的会议在这举行.
Jason: Mike, come on.My session's down here.
迈克:嗨,爸爸,你知道这里也有真的医生.
Mike: Hey Dad, you know they got real doctors here too.
杰森:你认为我是什么?
Jason: Who do you think I am?
迈克:我不知道.
Mike: I don't know.
杰森:行了.我们要错过我们的会议.
Jason: Come on.We're gonna miss our workshop.
迈克:爸爸,在那里我们干什么?
Mike: Dad, what are we gonna do in there?
杰森:所有诊所的临床医学医生正在实验一些关于家庭内交流的技术.
Jason: Well all of the clinic therapists are experimenting with some intra-
family communication techniques.
迈克:哦……他们不会把那些电的东西挂在我的头上吧,是吗?
Mike: Oh...they're not gonna hook up some electrical to my head, are they?
临床医学专家:哦,杰森,你在这!
Therapist: Oh, Jason, you're here!Good.Excuse me.
很好.对不起.
Doctors, would you take your seats, please.
医生,你能坐下吗,请.
I see each of you has brought a practice partner, very well.
我看到你们每个人带来了实验搭档,很好.
I sincerely hope that today's workshop will provide all of you with valuable
我真诚的希望今天的会议会给你们所有人提供有价值的经验,为有孩子和父母关系障碍提供咨询服务.谢谢.
exercises for counseling dysfunctional child-parent relationships.Thank you.
迈克:恩.这不会太无聊.快点,出去买碎肉夹饼.
Mike: Hmm.That wasn't too boring.Come on, let's go get a burger.
杰森:嗨,快点!坐下.
Jason: Hey, come on!Sit down.
男孩:妈妈一直太忙,
Boy: Mom always too busy, and you know...
你知道……你知道我真的认为她赶走了爸爸.
you know I really think that she drove away my father.
临床医学专家:很好,汉克.米勒医生,
Therapist: Very good, Hank.Doctor Miller, your turn.
轮到你了.记住,就像汉克的妈妈跟他说话;忘记你是个临床医学专家.
Remember, speak to Hank as his mother; forget you're a therapist.Dr.
米勒医生:行.现在,
Miller: Alright.Now, my son never tries to see anyone's point of son but
我儿子从来不试图理解别人的观点,除了他自己的.
his own.
杰森:圆形分格统计图表.
Jason: Pie chart.
迈克:很好.
Mike: Nice.
男孩:听着,家里不是这么回事,根本不是!!
Boy: Now look, that's not how it is at home, at all!!
米勒医生:汉克,别开自己玩笑!行,你被关禁闭了!我不仅仅是……(她开始对她儿子尖叫.)
Dr.Miller: Hank, don't kid yourself!Alright you're grounded!I'm not just...(she starts screaming at her son)
临床医学专家:好了,你现在可以停下来了.
Therapist: Alright, you can stop now.Dr.
米勒医生:谢谢.在座的每位,
Dr.Miller: Thank you.
你们刚才已经看到作出反应的典型例子.米勒医生,汉克.
Everyone, you've just seen classic example of a reactive response taking over.
你们现在可以回到座位上.那么现在,谁愿意下一个?
Doctor Miller.Hank.You can go back to your seats now.
哦,我们有自告奋勇的.
Well now, who wants to go next?Oh, we have a volunteer.
迈克:哦,不.不,不,我在打哈欠.
Mike: Oh, no.No, no, I was just yawning.
杰森:不,快点,嗨,我们去,迈克
Jason: No, come on, hey, we'll go Mike.
迈克:哦,呃……不,
Mike: Oh, err...no, no, really err...
不,真的呃……其他人可以下一个,我在这学了很多.
somebody else can go next, I'm really learning a lot here.
我想如果我最后的话,我会表现的更好些.
I think it will be a lot wackier if I went last.
临床医学专家:那么如果这能够使得你更舒服些,
Therapist: Well if it would make you more comfortable,
我可以分配你一些个人角色,而不是你自己,
I could assign your personality traits, other than your own,
那么你可以表现出来.
and you could act those out.
迈克:啊?
Mike: Huh?
杰森:是的,当我们在谈话的时候,我们假装成其他人.
Jason: Yeah, when we're talking we'll be pretending to be other people.
临床医学专家:很确切.因此,
Therapist: Exactly.So, for the next few minutes, Doctor Seaver,
在接下来的几分钟,西维尔医生,
why don't you adopt the persona of a father who's say...err...
你为什么不扮演父亲的角色,一个怎么说……呃……过分挑剔,认为他每件事情都正确,
overly precise, thinks he's right about everything,
崇拜事情有序为了自己的利益.你明白这个类型的人吗?
worships order for its own sake.You know the type?
杰森:我有了一些概念.
Jason: I've some idea.
迈克:一些概念!
Mike: Some idea!
临床医学专家:而迈克,
Therapist: And Mike, let's say you're a little immature for your age...
我们假设,你有点不成熟……呃……以自我为中心,
err...kind of the self-centered sort with an arrested adolescence and err...
还有具有青春期和呃……仅仅对轻佻的行为感兴趣.
interested only in the frivolous.
迈克:我作为一个专业演员,
Mike: Well being the professional actor that I am,
我想我能做到.
I think I can stretch that far.
杰森:专业演员!哈!哈!
Jason: Professional actor!Ha!Ha!
临床医学专家:行,那么我就要求你们进入指定的角色,
Therapist: Alright, so I want you to get into these assigned personas
而且只是……说你感觉到的.
and just...say what you feel.
迈克:爸爸,爸爸,你在干什么?
Mike: Dad, Dad what are you doing?
杰森:恩.我认为医生喜欢向外行解释.
Jason: Hmm.I think Dr.likes to explain to a layman.
临床医学专家:你在干什么?
Therapist: What are you doing?
杰森:我在准备.我准备好了.
Jason: I'm getting ready.I'm ready.
临床医学专家:迈克:你感觉怎么样?
Therapist: Mike, how do you feel?
迈克:十分不安.
Mike: Pretty embarrassed.
杰森:行了,你必须制造点冲突.
Jason: Come on, you've got to come up with some conflict.You can do that.
你可以做到.他经常这样做.
He always does that.
迈克:呃……爸爸,我有点不习惯这种关系,对我来说理解比较困难.
Mike: Errm...Dad, I'm just not used to this kind of relating, it's hard for me to understand.
杰森:就,快点,试试.
Jason: Just, come on, give it a try.
迈克:好的.爸爸,
Mike: OK.Dad, I'm just not like you,
我只是不象你,我从来不喝过期的牛奶,尽管闻起来是好的.
I just can't drink milk afar the expiration date just because it smells OK.
杰森:好,很有趣.谢谢你,很有趣.
Jason: OK, very funny.Thank you, very funny.
迈克:爸爸,爸爸,
Mike: Dad, Dad, I...
我……我不会为了备用而身上带两块手帕.
I can't carry around an extra pair of odor eaters just in case.
杰森:现在我们要严肃,要严肃.
Jason: Now let's be serious, be serious.
迈克:哎,该死,
Mike: Gosh, darn it, the heck anyway Dad!
不管怎么说,爸爸!
I just can't pay a guy for a haircut who's just as good as a licensed
我不会付钱给那个跟有执照的人理发一样好的人,只是因为他那里便宜几块钱.
barber just because he's a few Dollars cheaper.
杰森:迈克,停下.
Jason: Mike, cut it off.
迈克:不,不,爸爸,
Mike: No, no, Dad, this isn't Mike talking;
这不是迈克在说;这是我扮演的角色在说.我不再对你那样说话.
this is this character I'm playing.I'd never talk to you like that.
哦,是的,我们在做的是一个严肃的心理实验.
Oh, yeah, this is some serious shrink exercises we're doing here.
杰森:我知道你在这干什么了,迈克,我知道.
Jason: I know what we're doing here Mike, I know.
迈克:哦,唉,
Mike: Oh, gosh, I just wish I'd have some out of date milk here 'cause
我真的希望我能有一些过期的牛奶,这样现在我们可以干杯了,爸爸.
I'd toast to you right now, Dad.
杰森:现在非常好.
Jason: Now that's very nice.
我的儿子,你应该原谅他,
My son, you'll have to excuse him,
他有时候有成为演员的幻想.
he has these fantasies about being an actor sometimes.
迈克:爸爸,爸爸,行了,我是演员.
Mike: Dad, Dad, come on, I am an actor.
杰森:是呀,那些是在脑海里进行的一些小话剧,你明白吗.
Jason: Yeah, and these are the little plays that go on in his head, you see.
迈克:小话剧!
Mike: Little plays!
杰森:哦,对不起,是不是不没有足够认真对待你的职业?
Jason: Oh, I'm sorry am I not taking your calling seriously enough?
迈克:不,爸爸,你没有.
Mike: No Dad, you're not.
杰森:跟你不认真对待我的职业很相象.
Jason: Much like you don't take my calling seriously.
迈克:哦,这也许能够让你开心,
Mike: Oh, so what it would make you happy if I went along with these little
如果继续这些小话剧游戏,而你们点点头和抚摩你的山羊胡子.
party games while you guys nod and stroke your goatees!
杰森:我也会和你一样高兴的,如果当你每次使用"演员"这个字眼的时候,
Jason: Well I'd be just as happy as you would be if I didn't roll my
我没有翻眼.
eyes every time you used the word "actor".
迈克:哦……哦,我明白了,
Mike: Oh...oh, so I get it, so you therapists,
这就是你们临床医学专家,这就是你每周所做的!
this is what you do every week!
你过来痛打每个其他的孩子来取乐.很好.
You come in you beat up on each other's kids for fun.Nice.
男孩:现在,如果我要是这样说,就会被胄揍?
Boy: Now, how come when I said that I got hit?
杰森:弗兰克医生,每一位,对不起;我儿子不是那个意思.
Jason: Dr.Frankovitz, everybody, excuse me; my son doesn't mean this.
迈克:是,我就是那个意思,
Mike: Yes I do, Dad!
爸爸!而且跟你说实话,我认为整件事情就是个胡说八道.
And to tell you the truth, I think this whole thing is a crock!
杰森:胡说八道……
Jason: A cro...
迈克:是的.
Mike: Yes!
杰森:胡说八道!
Jason: A crock!
迈克:是的!我认为这是胡说八道,
Mike: Yes!I think it's a crock, Dad!
爸爸!我意思说,你从我的情况里得到的东西怎么能够对其他人有作用?
I mean, is how's your getting on my case gonna help these people at all?
杰森:我根本没有料想到"家庭冲突"研讨会成了你和我吵架的地方.
Jason: Well I hardly think that a seminar on "the family conflict" is
the right place for you and I to have a fight.
临床医学专家:澄清一点,这不是冲突研讨会,
Therapist: Just to be clear, this is not a seminar on conflict,
这是沟通研讨会.
it's a seminar on communication!
杰森:哦,闭嘴!哦,对……对不起,
Jason: Oh, shut up!Oh, I'm...
对不起,我发火了,我儿子使得我……
sorry, I'm sorry, I'm upset that my son's got me...
迈克:哦,很好;你朝我嚷嚷,
Mike: Oh, fine; you yell at me and I get blamed for it!Great!
我却被责备!很好!
I'm just glad I wasn't around for world war two,
我很庆幸我没有处在第二次世界大战,不然责备我发动了战争.
I would have been blamed for the Alamo!
杰森:因此,我……我为我儿子的无礼讲话表示道歉.
Jason: So, I...I apologise for my son's irrational display.
临床医学专家:别那么谦虚;你的讲话也不赖.
Therapist: Don't be so modest; yours was pretty good too.
克莉丝:开萝尔!开萝尔!开萝尔!
Chrissy: Carol!Carol!Carol!
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
克莉丝:妈妈想要知道是是否真的打扫了洗手间,还是只是偷懒?
Chrissy: Mom wants to know if you're really cleaning the bathrooms, or just goldbricking
开萝尔:是,我打扫了.我花了两个小时才发现那里面有地砖.
Carol: Yes I am.It took me two hours to discover we have tile in there.
本:我会记得你的.
Ben: I'll be thinking about you.
开萝尔:不公平.
Carol: It's not fair.
我是说,谁规定我就得洗厕所,
I mean, where is it written that I have to scrub toilets and Mike has
而迈克就得出去和爸爸快乐?
to go out and have fun with Dad?
杰森:迈克!你在那里干什么呢?下车!
Jason: Mike!What are you doing out here?Get off that car!
迈克:哦,好的,对我嚷嚷,但是如果是其他孩子坐在车上,你不会对他嚷嚷.
Mike: Oh, fine, yell at me, but when that other kid sat on the car
you didn't yell at him
杰森:我也会.
Jason: I did too.
迈克:哦,是呀,是呀……你笑了,你碰碰拳头,而且你看起来很蠢.
Mike: Oh, yeah, yeah...you laughed, you bumped fists and you looked silly.
杰森:我花了一个月才学会碰拳头.你刚才说的里面是什么意思,
Jason: Well it took me a month to get that fist bumping thing down anyway.
迈克?我意思是说,
What was the point of that in there, Mike?
你真的对我的工作这么蔑视?
I mean do you really have such contempt for my work?
而且对我的和你的事业不尊重?那么……
And so little respect for my calling and for me?Well...
迈克:听着,爸爸,如果我们不讲的话,那是更好,对吗?
Mike: Look Dad, it would be better if we didn't talk, alright?
临床医学专家:休息结束!进来讨论.
Therapist: Break's over!It's time to come in and communicate.
临床医学专家:好了,我们请西维尔父子从我们刚才离开的时候开始讲. 迈克和杰森:不!
Therapist: Alright, let's have the Seavers start right in where we left off.Mike and
Jason: No
米勒德:你们需要真正的难题,跟我前夫的儿子谈谈吧.
Dr.Millard: You want real problems, talk to my ex-husband's son.
临床医学专家:我们继续西维尔父子的谈话,
Therapist: We're going to continue with the Seavers because in the confines
因为在讨论会的范围内,
of this workshop, we should stick to those situations that offer some
我们需要研究带有希望的案例.
semblance of hope.
迈克:听着,我再次回到这里的原因是,
Mike: Look, the only reason I came back in here,
是因为我认为我没有必要在讲什么.
was because I thought I didn't have to talk anymore.
临床医学专家:现在,我有个想法,
Therapist: Now, I've got an idea that can turn this tension into,
某个东西能改变这种紧张,这个东西叫作,润滑剂.
what I'd like to call, a lubricant.
迈克:为什么你们不把电线什么的挂到我头上?!
Mike: Oh, why don't you just hook up something electrical to my head?!
临床医学医生:我们尝试角色互换.现在,
Therapist: We're gonna try some role reversal.
我需要你是父亲,你是儿子.
Now, I want you to be the father, and I want you to be the son.
杰森:我知道角色互换是什么意思.谢谢,
Jason: I know what role reversal is.Thank you, I am a psychiatrist.
我是精神病专家.这里的每为位都知道吗?
Does everybody here understand that?
临床医学专家:我知道,西维尔医生.你是父亲.你是儿子.开始.
Therapist: I know, Doctor Seaver.You're the father.You're the son.Go for it!
杰森:哦,我真高兴见到你们终于打扫屋子了.
Jason: Well, I'm glad to see you're finally cleaning up around the house.
瞧,地上有麦片.
Look, there's some cereal on the floor.
迈克:爸爸,那只是个意外.
Mike: Dad, that was an accident.
杰森:我不是爸爸,我是迈克.
Jason: I'm not Dad, I'm Mike.
迈克:行了.唉,
Mike: Alright.Well, you know, son,
你知道,儿子,
you promised me you'd go down to the old clinic with me,
你答应我去那个老诊所的,你应该把这记下来.
you know you should write these things down.
杰森:什么,那不是跟你一样傻吗?
Jason: What, and be like dumb old you?
迈克:孩子,
Mike: Boy, I've had enough of this attitude.
我受够这种态度了.
You know the least you could do,
你知道至少你可以做的是,回去和我合作,
is to go back in there and cooperate and stop embarrassing me in front
不要在我同事面前让我丢脸.
of my colleagues.
杰森:行,够了.
Jason: Alright, enough.I never should have brought you down here, Mike.
我真不应该把你带到这里,迈克.
I should have known that you wouldn't take this any more seriously than
我应该知道,你不会认真对待这件事情的.
you take the rest of your life.
迈克:哦,不,不,不.你不能走,你会毁掉我的圆形分格统计表.
Mike: Oh, no, no, no.You can't leave, you'll ruin my pie chart.
杰森:……到家我也不想听你说一个词;甚至到那时侯,我也不想听另外一个词.
Jason: ...a word out of you until we get home; and even then,
车钥匙……
I don't wanna hear another word.Car keys...
迈克:在你的裤兜里.
Mike: In your pant's pocket.
杰森:我说,你一句话也别说.你为什么不直接向我吐唾沫,迈克?
Jason: I said, not another word.Why didn't you just spit on me in there, Mike?
呵?呵?哦,你怎么不说话了?
Huh?Huh?Oh, you're not gonna say anything!
迈克:你说的,一个词都别说.
Mike: You said, not another word.
杰森:哦,现在你听话了.
Jason: So, now you behave in private.
在那里,在我的同事面前,
In there, in front of my colleagues, it's like you're Hitler's son.
你就像希特勒的儿子.我是经过培训的专家,
I'm a trained professional,
我知道如何以平静,理性和有同情心的态度处理突发情形.
I know how to handle volatile situations in a calm, rational,
你怎么能这么对我,迈克.
compassionate manner.How the hell can you do this to me, Mike!
迈克:爸爸,你在那里没有让我感到好受.我是说,说我所有的话剧,一文不值.取笑我那成为演员的梦想.
Mike: Dad, you didn't make me feel so hot in there.I mean, calling all
of my plays, little!You making fun of my dream to become an actor
杰森:哦,这就是你所想的;我取笑你的梦想?
Jason: Oh, is that what you think; I'm making fun of your dream?
迈克:是的,你取笑了.
Mike: Yes, you are!
杰森:我不知道为什么你不能更加的理解我,迈克.
Jason: I don't know how you cannot understand me better than that, Mike.
我不知道为什么我们差异这么大.
I don't know how we can be so different.
佛洛伊德:嗨,我要在这睡觉呢.
Floyd: Hey, I'm trying to sleep in here.
杰森:劳埃德!
Jason: Lloyd!
劳埃德:好呀,医生.
Lloyd: Hi ya, Doc.
杰森:你在这干什么,劳埃德?
Jason: What are you doing here, Lloyd?
劳埃德:我们有个会议,是吗?
Lloyd: We got a session, don't we?
杰森:那在下周六,劳埃德!
Jason: That's next Saturday, Lloyd!
劳埃德:哦,那么我早了;很好.
Lloyd: Oh, so I'm early; good.
杰森:哦,行了,
Jason: Oh, come on,
在大厅医生休息室里有非常舒适的沙发,好吗?
there's a real comfortable sofa just down the hall in the doctor's lounge, OK?
劳埃德:哦,多谢.
Lloyd: Oh, much obliged.
杰森:我还以为你不再喝酒了.
Jason: I thought you weren't drinking anymore.
劳埃德:我没有!
Lloyd: I'm not!
杰森:你手里是什么?
Jason: What's that in your hand?
劳埃德:是空的.我要保持我的一贯形象.
Lloyd: It's an empty.I have a certain reputation to uphold.
迈克:嗨,爸爸,你会怎么做,如果你看见我蜷缩在桌子里面?
Mike: Hey, Dad, what would you do if you saw me curled up inside this desk?
杰森:我会很高兴见到你离我工作的地方这么近.
Jason: I'd be thrilled to see you that close to a place where work happens.
迈克:哦,明白!明白!
Mike: Oh, see!See!See, that's exactly what's wrong with you.
明白,那就是你的错误所在.你甚至对待病人比对我好.
You even treat your patients better than you treat me.
杰森:哦,什么?
Jason: Oh, what?
迈克:是真的.我是说,就像那个男孩,
Mike: It's true.I mean, like this guy, Lloyd, and the kid outside.
劳埃德,和那个外面的孩子.我是说,
I mean, whatever they do, it's fine.But heck, I mean, if I...
无论他们做什么,都没关系.但是,我是说,
if I come in and I steal a couple of cheese puffs, you're...you're...you're...
如果我……如果我进来偷了几个奶酪饼干,你会……你会……你会……你数数数量,然后把他们算到我的房租里面.
you count 'em up and you add 'em onto my rent!
杰森:我干过一次,
Jason: I did that once, Mike.
迈克.
And the only reason I did that was to teach you something for the rest
我那样做的唯一原因是为你的今后让你接收一些教训.
of your life!
迈克:你怎么帮助我的今后的生活,爸爸,当我们是完全不同的时候?
Mike: How can you help me with the rest of my life, Dad,
我们完全不同!我是说,你说是,
when we are so completely different?We're totally different!
我说不.你说纸,我说塑料.
I mean, you say yes, I say no.You say paper, I say plastic.
杰森:我喜欢塑料,迈克!只是我认为它对环境没有好处.
Jason: I like plastic, Mike!I just don't think it's environmentally responsible.
迈克:爸爸,你只是在试图把我变成小的你.
Mike: Dad, you're just trying to turn me into another little you.
杰森:哦,我没有.
Jason: Oh, I am not.
迈克:是,承认吧!承认吧!这是你秘密鬼计划.
Mike: Yes, admit it!Admit it!It's your secret sick little plan.
杰森:它不是.
Jason: It is not.
迈克:是,它是.
Mike: Yes it is.OK.OK.
好.好.那是谁的主意,
Then whose idea was it for me to start putting my clothes away in
让我按字母顺序把衣服收拾好?啊?
alphabetical order?Huh?
杰森:那么,我告诉你吧,
Jason: Well then, let me tell you this, Mike;
迈克;你见过我连续两天穿同样的衣服吗?
have you ever seen me repeat clothing two days in a row?
迈克:是呀,我花了几个星期都没有找到地方放内裤.
Mike: Yeah, it took me weeks to figure out where I had to put my BVD'S.
杰森:那就是为什么它叫内衣,迈克.是内衣.是内……内衣!
Jason: That's why it's called underwear, Mike.It's underwear!It's under U!Underwear
迈克:面对它,面对它,爸爸!要面对它,你应该变得完美.我是说你做的每件事情!我是说甚至你的表现方式,穿衣方式,我是说,甚至你的头发!一切!
Mike: Face it, face it Dad!Let's just face it; you have to be perfect
I mean everything you do!I mean even the way you act, the way you
dress, I mean, even your hair!Everything
杰森:不,我没有,迈克,我没有必要变的完美.瞧,瞧,看看!
Jason: No, I don't Mike, I don't have to be perfect.See, see, look!
迈克:爸爸,你不会持续十秒钟不去动你的梳子的.
Mike: Dad, you can't last ten seconds without reaching for your comb.
杰森:我不明白头发凌乱的坐在这里与我们试图证明的事情有什么联系,
Jason: I don't see what sitting here with messy hair has to do with anything
迈克.
we're trying to prove here, Mike.
迈克:哈!我知道,我知道!
Mike: Ha!I knew it, I knew it!
杰森:你知道什么,
Jason: You know what,
像这样小的习惯可能会改变你对此的整个看法,
a little discipline like this just might change your whole outlook on this,
迈克.
Mike.
迈克:是,我知道,爸爸,但是吓到我了!
Mike: Yeah, I know, Dad, and it frightens me!
杰森:哎,实际一点没有什么不对,迈克.我是说,那么至少你有放弃某些事情.
Jason: Well, there's just nothing wrong with being a little practical, Mike.
(迈克结束了和杰森的谈话.)迈克,我从来没有说过你必须完全放弃表演.我只是说,我想让你实际点.
I mean, then
at least you have something to fall back on.(Mike finishes the sentence with Jason
Mike, I never said you had to give up acting all together.I just said
I want you to be realistic
迈克:但是如果你有事情要放弃,你最好放弃.
Mike: But if you have something to fall back on, you might as well fall back.
我是说,那有用吗?那好象准备好去放弃.
I mean, what's the use?It's like getting ready to give up.
杰森:不,这不是放弃,迈克,这只是建议.
Jason: No, it's not giving up, Mike, it's just sound advice.
迈克:那,你怎么知道,爸爸?你从来没有感受到我的感受.
Mike: Well, how do you know, Dad?You never felt what I feel.
杰森:你错了,迈克.我感受了.
Jason: You're wrong Mike.I do.
我明白,因为一端时间,
I know because there was a time, a long time ago when I made a mistake,
很长时间之前,当我犯了错误,我爸爸挽救了我.
and my dad straightened me out.
迈克:哦,是不是那时侯你准备留络腮胡子,
Mike: Oh, was that when you were gonna grow those little sideburns out
像爱尔维斯那样?
to look like Elvis?
杰森:噢,我留胡子是有原因的,
Jason: Well, I grew them for a reason Mike.
迈克.我留胡子,
I grew them because I too had a crazy fantasy.
因为我也有个疯狂的幻想.我认为我某天也能成为摇滚明星,
I thought I was gonna become a rock star one day, and I thank God,
但是我得感谢上帝,我爸爸挽救了我.
my dad helped straighten me out.
迈克:是呀,那么爷爷怎么确信某天你不能成为着名的摇滚明星,
Mike: Yeah, well how could Grandpa be so sure that one day you wouldn't
像……呃……
become a famous rock star like...err...
杰森:尼尔 岱尔蒙德.
Jason: Neil Diamond.
迈克:谁?
Mike: Who?
杰森:"我为何伤心?"……"肯塔基女人." (唱)肯塔基女人,她开始了解你.是呀!我为什么伤心?嘣,嘣,嘣,嘣,去没人的地方.嘣,嘣,嘣,嘣.不仅进一张椅子.
Jason: "Why am I sad?"..."Kentucky Woman." (singing) Kentucky woman, she get to know you
Yeah!Why am I sad?Bom Bom, Bom Bom, to no one there.Bom Bom
Bom Bom.Not even a chair
迈克:哦,是呀,尼尔 岱尔蒙德.
Mike: Oh, yeah, Neil Diamond.
杰森:尼尔 岱尔蒙德.
Jason: Neil Diamond.
劳埃德:现在唱,"撕裂黑夜"!
Lloyd: Now do, "Crackin' Rosie"!
杰森:撕裂……哦,劳埃德,出去!
Jason: Crackin....Oh, Lloyd, get out!Go on!
继续!供参考,
For your information Mike, the state of Delaware did not agree with Grandpa;
迈克,特拉华州没有同意爷爷,我和我的乐队有一年获得在特拉华州的比赛的奖项.
me and my band won the talent contest at the Delaware state fair one year.
迈克:哦,哇……我确信你喜欢在爷爷面前炫耀.
Mike: Oh wow...I bet you liked waving that in Grandpa's face.
杰森:啊.不,我没有在我父亲的面前炫耀,
Jason: Yeah.No, I didn't wave anything in my dad's face, Mike; unlike me,
迈克;不象我,他不是个通情达理的人.不,
he was not a reasonable man.
他只是给我一个选择,他说,
No, he just gave me a choice, he said, you got a choice,
你有一个选择,你去上医学院,或者你可以继续你的愚蠢行为跟着你的乐队.
you got medical school or you can follow this foolishness with your band.
迈克:那么你选择了医学院?
Mike: And you chose medical school.
杰森:不.不,
Jason: No.No, I chose foolishness.
我选择了愚蠢.我们有机会为美国音乐台试听,
We had a chance to audition for American Bandstand, with Dick Clarke,
和迪克 克拉克,因为以发觉新乐队闻名.
because he was famous for discovering new bands.
迈克:谁?
Mike: Who?
杰森:迪克 克拉克 错误,错误和错误."
Jason: Dick Clarke."Foul-ups, Bloopers and Blunders."
迈克:哇,你见了他!
Mike: Wow, you met him!
杰森:他那时侯很老了.
Jason: He was a lot older then.
因此,我父亲对我说,
So, with my dad saying, don't you come back,
你别回来了,
the whole band drove to Philadelphia.
整个乐队搬迁到费城.我们开了整夜车,
We drove all night, stayed in the most expensive hotel in town...
住在镇上最昂贵的宾馆……那时侯我们信心十足.
that's how sure we were.
迈克:好呀,然后发生什么了?
Mike: Yeah, and what happened?
杰森:好,这么说,我们由于花光了钱而结束了.我别无选择,只好回家,告诉我父亲发生的事情,你知道他说什么?
Jason: Well, let's just say, we ended up skipping out of the bill.I had no choice but to go back and tell my dad what happened and you know what he said?
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
杰森:我已经告诉你了.
Jason: I told you so.
迈克:什么?这是他所能做的最好的事情.
Mike: What?That was the best he could do.
杰森:唉,你不明白.我是说,他真正所说的是……他可以把事情搞惨.但是他知道在那个时候对我最好的事情就是让我伤心.
Jason: Well, you don't understand.I mean, what he was really saying...he could have made a big tragedy out of it.But he knew at the time that the
best thing for me was to have my heart broken
迈克:哦,不,但是,爸爸,
Mike: Oh, no but, Dad, you're nuts!
你发疯了!他至少可以说一些例如,对不起失败了儿子,
He could have at least said something like, sorry it didn't work out son,
或者嗨,你尽力了,或者我爱你,或者其它.
or hey you gave it your best shot, or I love you, or something.
杰森:是呀,或者他可以把他的手放在我肩膀上.
Jason: Yeah, or he could have put his hand on my shoulder.
迈克:是呀,或者她可以说那……那……那样你……你的乐队可以周末演出.
Mike: Yeah, or he could have said tha...tha...that you...you're band could play at weekends.
杰森:可以说,嗨,你知道吗,迪克 克拉克,你是个蠢货.
Jason: Could have said, hey, you know, Dick Clarke you're a jerk!
迈克:是呀!那是我的意思.我是说,什么使得他……
Mike: Yeah!That's my point.I mean, what made him...
杰森:什么使得他认为我所做的无关紧要!
Jason: What made him think that what I wanted didn't matter!
迈克:是!准确.
Mike: Yeah!Exactly.
杰森:是呀.
Jason: Yeah.
迈克:也许你像我.
Mike: Maybe you were like me.
杰森:我像.
Jason: I was.
杰森和迈克:我不相信.
Mike and Jason: I don't believe this.
迈克:等一下……那意味着,哪一天我也许会变成你这样.
Mike: Wait a minute...this means that someday I may turn into you.
爸爸,会突然发生吗?
Dad, does it happen all at once?
杰森:嗨,迈克,对不起,我嘲笑了你的表演废话.
Jason: Hey, Mike, I'm sorry that I put you down about that acting nonsense.
迈克:废话!
Mike: Nonsense!
杰森:我意思是说,事情……表演事情.
Jason: I mean, thing...the acting thing.
迈克:事情!
Mike: Thing!
杰森:我是说……你的梦想.我今天学到了很多.
Jason: I mean...your dream.I've learned a lot today.
迈克:是呀,我也是.
Mike: Yeah, me to.
我是说,有机会的话,
I mean, I better go and screw around while I got a chance, I mean...
我最好出去鬼混,我是说……结尾到了.
the end is coming.
杰森:你明白,
Jason: You know, it's not all bad to be just a little bit practical and
实际一点和有点责任心不全是坏事.
responsible too.
迈克:爸爸,当改变来临时,会痛苦吗?对不起,爸爸,只是整个事情对我来说是个触动.
Mike: Dad, when the change comes, does it hurt?I'm sorry Dad, it's just that
the whole thing is a bit of a shock to me
杰森:你怎么认为我的感受的?我发现这个世界上最烦恼我的人和我相象.
Jason: How do you think I feel?
I found out that the person that frustrates me most in the entire world
is just like me.
迈克:哦,是的,你也后悔参加这个讨论会?
Mike: Oh, yeah, so kind of sorry you came to this workshop thing too?
杰森:没有.迈克:我不明白你,爸爸.等一下,我明白了.哦,
Jason: No. Mike: I don't get you, Dad.Wait a minute, I do understand.
不,变化开始了,变化开始了,的确痛苦.00:21:41,600
Oh, no, it's happening, it's happening and it does hurt.